<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Blackjack Dealer</name>
    <directory>blackjack dealer</directory>
    <id>2599546253</id>
    <description>[h1] Time to fuel your gambling addiction with the Blackjack Dealer mod! [/h1]

This mod adds a blackjack dealer beggar to [b]arcade rooms[/b].

The default spawn chance is 50% (although you can use [b]Mod Config Menu[/b] to change it) to replace any machine, beggar or shell game in an arcade room.

To play blackjack - you simply walk up to him. One game costs [b]5 cents[/b]. If you win, you get your coins back on top of the reward.

[b]How to play blackjack? Check the Discussions or [url=https://www.blackjackapprenticeship.com/how-to-play-blackjack/] look it up. [/url][/b]

[b]Controls:[/b]
[list]
[*]Shoot left/right - Change the arrow to go hit/stand
[*]Bomb - Trigger the action selected by the arrow
[*]Drop - Leave the menu
[/list]
[b]Payouts:[/b]
[list]
[*]40% - 1 &quot;Special&quot; card which is basically just a playing card.
[*]20% - 2 Random cards
[*]15% - 1 Lucky penny &amp; 2 normal pennies
[*]10% -  2 Keys &amp; 2 bombs
[*]5% - 1 Dime
[*]4% - 1 Random item from the claw machine item pool
[*]3% - 1 Chest
[*]2% - 1 Random Trinket
[*]1% - Destruction of the beggar
[/list]

The beggar/dealer npc's type is 6 and the variant is 72, so you can spawn it with [code] spawn 6.72 [/code]

[b]Possible future additions:[/b]
Increase the max amount of cards, so that they don't get off the paper after more than 7 cards

[b] Bug notice: [/b]
Sometimes when the player/dealer hits the card isn't added but the sound plays. Also sometimes the dealer's hidden card isn't shown. 
I have no clue what causes these bugs, however [b]I believe they're completely harmless and don't substancially affect gameplay[b].

Thanks to Discowy 2.0 for the help with sprites and balancing.

You can check this mod's github repo [url=https://github.com/ddeeddii/tboi_blackjack_dealer] here [/url]</description>
    <version>1.7</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
</metadata>
